Harlan Fiske Stone Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Harlan Fiske Stone Papers 1889-1950 1925-1946
MSS41574
Stone, Harlan Fiske, 1872-1946
26,500 items
87 containers
36.3 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Attorney general, associate and chief justice of the Supreme Court, and educator. Professional and family correspondence, writings, reports, legal case files, biographical information, and other material relating primarily to Stone's service on the Supreme Court.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Brant, Irving, 1885-1976.; Burlingham, Charles C. (Charles Culp), 1858-1959--Correspondence.; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947--Correspondence.; Carr, Sterling, 1876- --Correspondence.; Douglas, William O. (William Orville), 1898-1980--Correspondence.; Dulles, John Foster, 1888-1959--Correspondence.; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965--Correspondence.; Hand, Learned, 1872-1961--Correspondence.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964--Correspondence.; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948--Correspondence.; Mason, Alpheus Thomas, 1899-1989--Correspondence.; Moore, John Bassett, 1860-1947--Correspondence.; Roberts, Owen J. (Owen Josephus), 1875-1955--Correspondence.; Smith, Luther Ely, 1873-1951--Correspondence.; Smith, Young B. (Young Berryman), 1889-1960--Correspondence.; Stone, Harlan Fiske, 1872-1946.; Stone, Lauson Harvey, 1904-1999--Correspondence.; Stone, Lauson, 1883-1948--Correspondence.; Stone, Marshall H. (Marshall Harvey), 1903-1989--Correspondence.; Sutherland, George, 1862-1942--Correspondence.; Willard, Helen Luthera Stone, 1886- --Correspondence.; Willebrandt, Mabel Walker, 1889-1963.
Organizations
Amherst College.; Columbia University. School of Law.; Folger Shakespeare Library.; National Gallery of Art (U.S.); Smithsonian Institution.; United States. Department of Justice. Office of the Attorney General.; United States. Supreme Court.
Subjects
Art museums--Washington (D.C.); Constitutional law--United States.; Law schools--New York (State)--New York.; Law--United States.; Libraries--Washington (D.C.); Museums--Washington (D.C.); Universities and colleges--Massachusetts--Amherst.
Occupations
Cabinet officers.; Educators.; Judges.; Justices, U.S. Supreme Court.; Lawyers.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Harlan Fiske Stone, attorney general, associate and chief justice of the Supreme Court, and educator, were given to the Library of Congress in 1949 by his wife, Agnes H. Stone.
Related Material
Related collections in the Manuscript Division include the papers of Hugo Lafayette Black, Harold H. Burton, William O. Douglas, Felix Frankfurter, Charles Evans Hughes, and John Bassett Moore.
Access and Restrictions
The Stone Papers are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1872, Oct. 11 Born, Chesterfield, N.H.
1888 1890 Student, Massachusetts Agricultural College
1894 B.S., Amherst College, Amherst, Mass.
1894 1895 Teacher, Newburyport high school, Newburyport, Mass.
1895 1896 Part-time teacher, Adelphi Academy, New York, N.Y.
1898 LL.B., Columbia University, New York, N.Y. Admitted to the bar
1898 1899 Clerk, Sullivan and Cromwell
1898 1903 Lecturer, Columbia Law School, Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
1899 Married Agnes Harvey
1899 1905 Associated with Wilmer and Canfield
1903 1905 Adjunct professor of law, Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
1905 1910 Lawyer, Wilmer and Canfield
1910 1923 Professor of law and dean of the law faculty, Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
1923 1924 Head of litigation department, Sullivan and Cromwell
1924 1925 Attorney general of the United States
1925 1941 Associate justice, U.S. Supreme Court
1941 1946 Chief justice of the United States
1946, Apr. 22 Died, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Harlan Fiske Stone (1872-1946) span the period 1889-1953, but most of the papers are dated 1925-1946 when Stone served on the Supreme Court of the United States. The collection consists of Family Correspondence, General Correspondence, Special Correspondence, Subject File, Supreme Court File, and Miscellany series.
Stone's Family Correspondence consists chiefly of letters exchanged between Stone and his brother Lauson, sister Helen, and sons Marshall and Lauson. Very few letters in the collection are between Stone and his wife, Agnes. Although Stone occasionally mentioned the Supreme Court or other issues of the day, the letters in this series are mainly concerned with personal and family matters.
The General Correspondence covers a broader range. It contains letters of recommendation supporting friends for various positions, Stone's comments on the large number of addresses and articles sent him by others in the legal profession, and discussions of court matters, the judicial process, legal education, and related subjects. His correspondence with Felix Frankfurter and John Bassett Moore is voluminous and relates mainly to legal affairs. Other correspondents in this series include Charles C. Burlingham, Nicholas Murray Butler, Sterling Carr, John Foster Dulles, Learned Hand, Herbert Hoover, Luther Ely Smith, Young Berryman Smith, and George Sutherland. The earliest letters in the collection are from Stone's high school teachers, Jessamine Dixon and Edith Field, in 1889-1892, and concern the course of his future education after being dismissed from Massachusetts Agricultural College.
In the Special Correspondence series are congratulatory messages that Stone received on his appointments as attorney general, associate justice, and chief justice, as well as the condolences received by the family after his death. In addition to the telegrams and rather perfunctory messages, there are communications commending Stone for his conduct in the various public offices he held, especially for his statement before the Senate Judiciary Committee in 1925 concerning his involvement in the prosecution of Senator Burton K. Wheeler of Montana.
Stone's varied interests and activities are reflected in the Subject File. His long service as a trustee of Amherst College and as a chairman of its committee on the Folger Shakespeare Library, and his abiding interest in these situations, are well documented. He also served as chairman of the board of trustees of the National Gallery of Art and as chancellor of the Smithsonian Institution; files on these institutions are also in this series. The Columbia University Law School material, which dates from 1899 to 1923, reflects Stone's connection with that institution, first as a teacher and later as dean. His interest in legal education is also reflected in the files on the American Law Institute and various bar associations. Other significant files in this series include those relating to Stone's efforts in appointing new U.S. attorneys during his tenure as attorney general.
The Supreme Court File, which contains correspondence, near-print and printed matter, and clippings, is divided into three subseries: Case Files, Correspondence, and General Office Files.
The Case files, which make up the largest part of the Supreme Court File, constitute a record of Stone's written opinions, concurrences, and dissents for his years on the court from the 1924 through 1945 terms. The cases are arranged chronologically by term and alphabetically therein by case name. The first folder of the case files contains a memorandum prepared by Stone's secretary explaining the color codes on the folder labels. Contained in the case files are printed drafts of opinions, memoranda on individual cases, and notes exchanged by the justices on the cases. The printed drafts of Stone's opinions that he circulated among the other justices (known as “returns”) often contain their comments on the back.
The Correspondence in the Supreme Court File is organized in two parts: correspondence with other justices and correspondence with attorneys and petitioners. The correspondence with other justices covers the years they served on the court with Stone; correspondence prior to this is located in the General Correspondence series. The justices' correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name and then chronologically. Files for William O. Douglas, Felix Frankfurter, Charles Evans Hughes, and Owen J. Roberts contain the largest amounts of correspondence. Stone's correspondence with attorneys and petitioners regarding cases before the court is arranged chronologically, and involves in the main procedural matters such as requests for extensions of filing deadlines. Also included is material concerning affairs of the Second Circuit to which Stone was assigned.
The General Office File subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject and contains correspondence with court officers such as the clerk and the reporter regarding administrative matters. The file also contains newspaper clippings and correspondence with the public concerning the court's procedures and decisions. Examples include clippings and letters sent to Stone supporting his dissent in the flag salute case of 1940 (Minnersville School District v. Gobitis).
Included in the Miscellany series are letters to Alpheus T. Mason, Stone's biographer, containing reminiscences of Stone by Irving N. Brant, Mabel Walker Williebrandt, and others, and clippings relating to Stone's life and a copy of a letter of 1907 by Theodore Roosevelt in which he defends his judicial appointments. Other material confirms Stone's reputation as a wine connoisseur.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in six series:
Family Correspondence, 1900-1946
General Correspondence, 1889-1946
Special Correspondence, 1924-1946
Subject File, 1899-1946
Supreme Court File, 1924-1946
Miscellany, 1907-1953
Container List
- Family Correspondence, 1900-1946 (Box 1-4)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent between family members, together with other family papers.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent and chronologically therein.
  - Harvey, Edward (brother-in-law), 1924, 1928-1934 (Box 1)
  - Harvey, Ella (Mrs. Herman) (mother-in-law), 1925-1934
  - Harvey, John C. (brother-in-law), 1924-1930
  - Henry, John P. (cousin), 1931
  - Stone, Agnes (Mrs. Harlan) (wife), 1924
  - Stone, David (nephew), 1927-1940
  - Stone, Lauson (brother)
    - 1924-1927
    - 1928-1930
    - 1931-1932
    - 1933-1934
    - 1935-1937
    - 1938-1946
  - Stone Lauson (son)
    - 1924-1927
    - 1928-1930
    - 1931-1933
    - 1934-1935
    - 1936-1937
    - 1938-1939 (Box 2)
    - 1940-1946
    - Letters concerning, 1924-1933
  - Stone, Margaret (Mrs. Winthrop) (sister-in-law), 1924-1935
  - Stone, Marshall (son)
    - 1924-1927
    - 1928-1932
    - 1933-1936
    - 1937-1939
    - 1940-1942
    - 1943-1945, undated
    - Letters concerning, 1924-1944
  - Stone, Marshall and Lauson (sons), from Harlan Fiske Stone
    - 1924-1925
    - 1926-1927
    - 1928
    - 1929-1930 (Box 3)
    - 1931-1932
    - 1933-1934
    - 1935-1936
    - 1937-1938
    - 1939-1940
    - 1941-1946
  - Stone, Mrs. Mary E. (aunt?), 1931-1932
  - Stone, Richard (nephew)
    - 1924-1938
    - 1939-1946
  - Stone, Winthrop E. (brother)
    - 1900
    - Loyalty investigation, 1918-1920
  - Willard, Helen Stone (sister)
    - 1924-1927
    - 1928-1929
    - 1930-1931
    - 1932
    - 1933 (Box 4)
    - 1934-1935
    - 1936-1937
    - 1938-1940
    - 1941-1946
  - Willard, Luthera (niece), 1930-1931
  - Willard, Mrs. Nina B. (Helen Stone Willard's mother-in-law), 1934-1940
- General Correspondence, 1889-1946 (Box 4-30)
  Letters received, copies of letters sent, and miscellaneous enclosures.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - “A” miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Ac-Ai
    - Al
    - Am-An
    - At-Ay
  - Abbot, Charles G. See Container 51, Smithsonian Institution
  - Abbott, Nathan
  - Aitchison, Clyde B.
  - Albright, Horace M.
  - Allen, Adéle
  - Allen, Madeline (Mrs. Raymond D.) (Box 5)
  - American Civil Liberties Union
  - American Law Institute
  - Amerine, Maynard A.
  - Ames, Joseph S.
  - Andrews, Alexander B.
  - Andrews, Paul Shipman
  - Aronson, Moses J.
  - “B” miscellaneous
    - Ba
    - Be
    - Bi-Bl
    - Bo
    - Br
    - Bu-By
  - Backus, Grosvenor H.
    - 1924-1933
    - 1934-1946
  - Balogh, Elemér (Box 6)
    - 1925-1934
    - 1935-1945
  - Bangs, Frederick C.
  - Bannister, L. Ward
  - Bartlett, John H.
  - Bates, Henry M.
  - Baxter, Harold See also Container 42, Attorney General's confidential file, Arizona
  - Beard, Charles A. and Mary R.
  - Beck, James M
  - Bell, Clinton E.
  - Berger, Raoul
  - Bigelow, Harry A.
  - Booth, William Stone
  - Borchard, Edwin M.
    - 1926-1933
    - 1934-1945
  - Boskey, Bennett
  - Bradley, Phillips
  - Brant, Irving (Box 7)
    - 1936-1937
    - 1938-1945
  - Bruce, Edward
    - 1932-1938
    - 1939-1942
  - Buckner, Emory R.
  - Burdick, Charles K.
  - Burlingham, Charles C.
    - 1925-1929
    - 1930-1939
    - 1940-1942
    - 1943-1946
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray See also Container 44, Columbia University and Containers 44-54, Columbia University Law School
    - 1925-1928
    - 1929-1941
  - “C” miscellaneous
    - Ca-Ce
    - Ch-Ci (Box 8)
    - Cl
    - Cog-Cor
    - Cos-Coy
    - Cr-Cu
  - Cameron, Ralph See Container 43, Attorney General's confidential file, Arizona
  - Canfield, George F.
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. See also Container 74, Cardozo
  - Carey, Homer F.
  - Carlsmith, Carl S.
  - Carr, Sterling See also Container 44, Attorney General's confidential file, Northern District-California
    - 1925-1926
    - 1927-1928
    - 1929
    - 1930-1932
    - 1933-1934
    - 1935-1937
    - 1938 (Box 9)
    - 1939
    - 1940
    - 1941
    - 1942
    - 1943
    - 1944
    - 1945-1946
  - Chafee, Zechariah, Jr.
  - Chalmers, Gordon K. See Container 48, Kenyon College
  - Chamberlain, Joseph P.
  - Cheatham, Elliott E.
  - Clark, Charles E.
  - Clemens, Cyril
  - Cogswell, Robert F.
  - Cohen, Julius Henry
  - Comins, Eben F.
  - Cook, Walter Wheeler See also Container 39, American Law Institute (Box 10)
    - 1924-1927
    - 1928-1943
  - Coolidge, Calvin
  - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague See Container 8, Cog-Cor; and Container 46, Folger Shakespeare Library, Miscellaneous
  - Corwin, Edward S.
  - Corwin, Hilary
  - Coudert, Alexis C.
  - Coudert, Frederic R.
  - Craig, Allan
  - Cromwell, William Nelson
    - 1925-1928
    - 1929-1943
  - Crozier, William
  - Cummings, Homer S.
  - Cummings, Wilbur L.
  - “D” miscellaneous
    - Da
    - De
    - Di-Do
    - Dr-Dy
  - Dale, Chester See Container 49, National Gallery of Art
  - Davis, Earl J.
  - Davis, John W.
  - Denman, William
  - Dickson, John
  - Dilliard, Irving
  - Dills, Duane R.
  - Dixon, Jessamine
  - Dobie, Armistead M. (Box 11)
  - Donovan, William J.
  - Dorr, Goldthwaite H.
  - Dowling, Noel T.
    - 1924-1928
    - 1929-1935
    - 1936-1946
  - Downey, Francis X.
  - Dulles, John Foster
    - 1926-1933
    - 1934-1946
  - Duncan, Frederick S.
  - Dunham, Allison
  - “E” miscellaneous
  - Edmonds, Douglas L.
  - Emery, Roe
  - Ernst, Richard P.
  - Eustis, Augustus H.
  - Evatt, Herbert Vere
  - “F” miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - Fa
    - Fe-Fi
    - Fl
    - Fo
    - Fr-Fu
  - Fairman, Charles
  - Falk, Edwin A.
  - Fallon, Perlie P.
  - Farley, James A.
  - Farnum, George R.
  - Farrand, George E. and Stephen M.
  - Farrand, Max See Container 12, Fa; and Container 45, Commonwealth Fund Legal Research Committee
  - Faust, George H.
  - Field, Edith
  - Finch, Edward R.
    - 1924-1927
    - 1928-1929
    - 1930-1935
    - 1936-1945
  - Finley, David E. See Container 12, Fi; Container 39, American Commission for the protection and Salvage of Artistic and Historic Monuments in Europe; and Containers 49-50, National Gallery of Art
  - Fiske, Brenton K.
  - Forbes, Henry H.
  - Foss, Wilson P.
  - Foss, Wilson P, Jr.
  - Frankfurter, Felix See also Containers 74-75, Frankfurter (Box 13)
    - 1927-1928
    - 1929-1930
    - 1931
    - 1932
      - Jan.-Apr.
      - May-Dec.
    - 1933-1934
    - 1935
      - Jan.-May
      - June-Dec.
    - 1936
      - Jan.-Feb.
      - Mar.
      - Apr.-Dec.
    - 1937
      - Jan.-Apr.
      - May-Dec.
    - 1938
    - 1939
  - Frizzell, John R.
  - “G” miscellaneous
    - Ga-Ge
    - Gi-Go
    - Gr-Gu
  - Ganter, Carl R. (Box 14)
  - Gardner, Warner W.
  - Gellhorn, Walter F.
  - Gilbert, Cass
  - Gilmore, Eugene A.
  - Glenn, Garrard
    - 1924-1927
    - 1928-1934
    - 1935-1944
  - Gluck, Edward
  - Goebel, Julius, Jr.
  - Goldin, Gullie B.
  - Goodrich, Herbert F. See also Container 39, American Law Institute
  - Graham, Edward M.
  - Green, Edward H.
  - Griffiths, Farnham P.
  - Griswold, Erwin N. (Box 15)
    - 1934-1938
    - 1939-1944
  - Groner, D. Lawrence
  - Grosvenor, Gilbert
  - “H” miscellaneous
    - Hac-Hard
    - Harl-Hay
    - He
    - Hi
    - Ho
    - Hu-Hy
  - Hale, Robert L.
  - Halifax, Edward Frederick Lindley Wood, 1st Earl of
  - Hanbury, Harold
  - Hand, Augustus N.
  - Hand, Learned
    - 1924-1933
    - 1934-1935
  - Handler, Milton (Box 16)
    - 1926-1930
    - 1931-1939
    - 1940-1949
  - Hardy, George E.
  - Harlan, Richard D. and Laura
  - Hart, Henry H.
  - Haskell, Henry J.
  - Hellman, George S.
  - Hertle, Louis
  - Hewitt, John Vance
    - 1927-1929
    - 1930-1935
    - 1936-1941
    - 1942-1946
  - Hicks, Frederick C.
    - 1925-1926
    - 1927-1928
    - 1929-1946
  - Holmes, Edward J. (Box 17)
  - Holt, Hamilton
  - Hoover, Herbert
    - 1925-1929
    - 1930-1939
    - 1940-1944
  - Hoover, J. Edgar
    - 1928-1934
    - 1935-1943
  - Howland, Charles P. See Container 45, Education
  - Hughes, Charles Evans See also Container 75, Hughes
  - Hull, Cordell See also Container 39, American Commission for the Protection and Salvage of Artistic and Historic Monuments in Europe
  - “I” miscellaneous
  - “J” miscellaneous
    - Ja
    - Je-Jo
  - Jackson, Robert H. See also Container 75, Jackson
  - Jahncke, Ernest Lee
  - Jervey, Huger C.
  - Jessup, Henry Wyans
  - Jessup, Philip C.
  - Johnson, Douglas W.
  - Johnson, Wilbur C. (Box 18)
  - Johnston, William S.
  - “K” miscellaneous
    - Ka-Ke
    - Ki
    - Kl-Ku
  - Kane, Albert E.
  - Kaufman, Joseph W.
  - Kenngott, George F.
  - Keppel, Frederick P. See also Container 39, American Law Institute
  - Kirschten, Ernest
  - Knox, John
  - Kress, Samuel H.
  - Kress (Samuel H.) Foundation
  - Krock, Arthur
  - “L” miscellaneous
    - La
    - Le
    - Li-Ly
  - Landis, James M. See also Container 47, Harvard University (Box 19)
  - Larremore, Thomas A.
  - Laski, Harold J.
  - Lehman, Irving
  - Leiby, Adrian C.
  - Lepaulle, Pierre
  - Levy, Beryl H.
  - Lewis, William Draper See Container 39, American Law Institute
  - Lewisohn, Sam A.
  - Lief, Alfred
    - 1936-1939
    - 1940-1945
  - Lips, Julius E.
  - Llewellyn, Karl N.
  - Loewenstein, Karl
  - Louw, Eric H.
  - Lusky, Louis
  - “M” miscellaneous
    - McA-McD
    - McE-McM
    - McN-Man
    - Mar-Max (Box 20)
    - Me
    - Mi
    - Mo
    - Mu-My
  - McBain, Howard Lee
  - MacChesney, Nathan William
  - McCormack, Alfred
  - McGovney, Dudley O.
  - Mack, Julian W.
  - Marshall, James
  - Marshall, John
  - Marshall, L.C.
  - Mead, Edwin D.
  - Medina, Harold R.
    - 1925-1931
    - 1932-1945
  - Mellon, Andrew W.
  - Merrill, Oliver B., Jr. (Box 21)
  - Meyer, Eugene See also Container 45, District of Columbia police situation
  - Michael, Jerome
    - 1925-1928
    - 1929-1931
    - 1933-1938
  - Mitchell, Mark D.
  - Mitchell, William DeWitt
  - Mittell, Sherman F.
  - Moe, Henry Allen
  - Montague, Gilbert H.
  - Moore, John Bassett
    - 1921, 1925
    - 1926
      - Jan.
      - Feb.-May
      - June-Dec.
    - 1927
    - 1928
    - 1929
    - 1930
    - 1931
    - 1932
    - 1933 (Box 22)
    - 1934-1935
    - 1936-1937
    - 1938-1939
    - 1940-1945
  - Moore, Underhill
  - Moore, William A.
  - Morawetz, Victor See Container 39, American Law Institute
  - Morgenthau, Henry, Jr.
  - Morley, Felix
  - Morris, George M. See Container 20, Mo; and Container 45, District of Columbia police situation
  - Morrisson, James Lord
  - Morrow, Dwight W. See also Container 49, Morrow
    - 1924-1929
    - 1930-1935
  - Munroe, Vernon S.
  - Murray, George Welwood
  - “N” miscellaneous
    - Na
    - Ne
    - Ni
    - No-Nu
  - Neff, Charles Melvin
  - Nelson, Carl Roger
  - Neylan, John Francis
  - Nickerson, Eugene H. (Box 23)
  - “O” miscellaneous
    - O'B-Old
    - Oln-Ow
  - O'Brian, John Lord
  - Olds, George D.
  - Olds, Robert E.
  - Oliphant, Herman
    - 1925-1928
    - 1929-1936
  - Orleans, Ilo Louis
  - Osterhout, Howard
    - 1925-1931
    - 1932-1937
    - 1938-1945
  - Otis, Merrill E.
  - “P” miscellaneous
    - Pa
    - Pe
    - Ph
    - Pi-Po
    - Pr-Pu
  - Parker, Edwin B.
  - Parker, John J. (Box 24)
  - Parkinson, Thomas I.
  - Parsons, Geoffrey
  - Patterson, Edwin W.
  - Pease, Arthur Stanley
  - Peckett, Robert P.
  - Pennell, Elizabeth Robins (Mrs. Joseph)
  - Pepper, George Wharton See also Container 39, American Law Institute
  - Peter, Marc and Jeanne
  - Pinchot, Gifford and Cornelia
  - Piper, Wilson C.
  - Platt, Charles A.
  - Pound, Roscoe See Container 47, also Harvard University
  - Powell, Richard R.
  - Powell, Thomas Reed
    - 1917, 1924-1931
    - 1932-1945
  - Prochnik, Edgar L. G.
  - “Q” miscellaneous
  - Quezon, Manuel L. See Container 51, Smithsonian Institution
  - “R” miscellaneous
    - Ra
    - Re-Rh
    - Ri
    - Rob-Roe
    - Rog-Roy
    - Ru-Ry
  - Rathbone, Robert C. (Box 25)
    - 1924-1926
    - 1927-1929
    - 1930-1945
  - Reynolds, Jackson E.
  - Richie, Lawerence
  - Ripley, William Z.
  - Ritter, William M.
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. See Container 39, American Commission for the Protection and Salvage of Artistic and Historic Monuments in Europe; Container 50, National Gallery of Art; and Container 51, Rubber, and Smithsonian Institution
  - Rosenberg, James N.
  - Rosenthal, Albert
  - Rostel, Ernest A.
  - Rowe, L. S.
  - Rugg, Arthur P. See Container 24, Ru-Ry; and Container 39, American Law Institute
  - Russell, Harold C.
  - “S” miscellaneous
    - Sa
    - Sc
    - Se
    - Sh
    - Si-Sk
    - Sl-Sm
    - Sn-Sp (Box 26)
    - Sta-Ste
    - Sti-Stu
    - Su-Sz
  - Saint-Gaudens, Homer
  - Sargent, John G.
  - Satterlee, Herbert L.
    - 1925-1933
    - 1934-1946
  - Scandrett, Richard B., Jr.
    - 1929-1932
    - 1935-1945
  - Schiffeler, Carl C.
  - Seligman, Eustaee
  - Seymour, Whitney North
  - Shein, Benjamin
  - Shoop, Max
    - 1924, Apr.-Jul.
    - 1924-1932, Jul.
  - Shriver, Harry C.
  - Simpson, Sidney Post
  - Smith, Barry C. See Container 45, Commonwealth Fund Legal Research Committee
  - Smith, Luther Ely (Box 27)
    - 1924-1926
    - 1927-1930
    - 1931-1936
    - 1937-1938
    - 1939-1940
    - 1941-1943
    - 1944-1946
  - Smith, Young B. See also Container 44, Columbia University; and Containers 44-45, Columbia University Law School
    - 1924-1926
    - 1927-1929
    - 1930-1931
    - 1932-1934
    - 1935-1938
    - 1939-1941
    - 1942-1946
  - Snell, Bertrand H.
  - Son, Charles A.
  - Stallcup, Evan S. See Container 43, Attorney General's confidential file, Arizona
  - Stearns, Alfred E. (Box 28)
  - Sterne, Maurice
  - Stettinius, Edward R., Jr. See also Container 51, State Department
  - Stoessel, Oskar
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps
  - Stone, Royal A.
  - Strawn, Silas H.
  - Sutherland, George See also Container 76, Sutherland
  - Swan, Thomas W.
  - Sykes, Emery H.
  - Sze, Sao-Ke Alfred
  - “T” miscellaneous
    - Ta-Te
    - Th-Ti
    - To-Tr
    - Ts-Tw